NNENNA NDUKWE

832-484-9125 Innenna.s.ndukwe@gmail.com

Detail oriented and versatile Computer Science student with an interest in software engineering and a career goal of providing technological opportunities for underrepresented communities. Creative and logical with experience in programming, software projects and web/app development. Experience in full-stack programming, social service, IT, academic, retail, and customer service fields.

- Web App Development | JavaScript
- Youth Development & Mentorship
- IT Tutoring

- HTML5/CSS3, Bootstrap 4, Sass Python development
- Consulting/Sales
- Java, JSON, VB.NET
- Creative Writing/Blogging
- Customer Service

EDUCATION

BOSTON UNIVERSITY | BOSTON, MA Computer Science 2020

Relevant Coursework: Honors Program with UMASS Amherst Fall 2016

• Ethics in Information Technology: a project-oriented course on cyber security, hacking, networking systems, information technology policies, & information systems RESILIENT CODERS | BOSTON, MA Sep 2017 - Dec 2017

Full Stack Web Development Coding Bootcamp

- Mongo Database, Express.js, React, Node.js, Pure JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3
- Mandatory freelance client acquisition
- Technical Interview training
- Client-side and server-side programming

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

COMMON SENSING | Cambridge, MA

Full Stack Web & Software Developer

Sep 2017-Present

- Develop internal software for device production with Python 3 & statistical engineering implementation
- Engineer front-end web application for clinical data utilizing React, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, JSX
- Debug, test, calibrate, engineer, and upgrade firmware versions for medical device product pipelining

Common Sensing | Cambridge, MA

June 2017-Sep 2017

Product & Software Engineering Intern

- Develop internal software with Python 3 language & statistical engineering implementation
- Testing iOS & Android applications, bug fixing, version control, code reviewing, and pair programming
- Automate engineering software tools for quality metrics and firmware accuracy/productivity
- Managing database of 10,000+ records for data analyses to determine product efficacy for clinical research
- Perform product performance testing, inspection, calibration, software upgrades, and Quality Control

ROXBURY COMMUNITY COLLEGE | Roxbury, MA

Aug 2016-June 2017

IT Computer Laboratory Assistant

- Responsible for maintaining 50+ computers and performing periodic software updates
- Provide assistance to 50+ students by handling questions & problems in a courteous, efficient manner
- Teach and guide student groups in using software such as Microsoft Word, Excel, Access & PowerPoint
- Tutor English, writing and essay articulation for ESL students in the Writing Lab via appointments

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

BLACK GIRLS CODE | Boston, MA

Nov 2016-Present

Tech Instructor Volunteer

- Oversee monthly coding classes for a 30+ girls between the ages of 8 and 17.
- Facilitate developmental and leadership workshops with kid coding software Kodu Game Lab
- Utilize fundamental Java/C computer science programming functions for kid programming

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

GIRL DEVELOP IT | Boston, MA

Nov 2016-Present

• Networking association for female software programmers

NAACP YOUTH COUNCIL PRESIDENT

June 2012-June 2014

Encouraged minority high school engagement in STEM via national ACT-SO STEM project competitions